<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-10-10T05:36:16-04:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kirill Dubovikov</title><subtitle>My thoughts on everything :)</subtitle><author><name>Kirill Dubovikov</name></author><entry><title type="html">Why study algorithms?</title><link href="/articles/programming/algo-study" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why study algorithms?" /><published>2022-10-07T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-07T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/articles/programming/algo-study</id><author><name>Kirill Dubovikov</name></author><category term="programming" /><summary type="html">In this post, we will look at a task dreaded by many: getting better at solving algorithmic challenges. Some think it’s worthless, others feel rage about the current hiring industry is blind to what’s really important. But we will try to look at this from another perspective to see if it’s worth to devote time to get skills necessary for solving computer science problems.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Employee is a non-performer? It is your fault. Act on it</title><link href="/articles/management/hiring-fault" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Employee is a non-performer? It is your fault. Act on it" /><published>2022-02-18T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-02-18T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/articles/management/hiring-fault</id><author><name>Kirill Dubovikov</name></author><category term="management" /><summary type="html">I want to start a new post topic. A part of future posts on this blog will be about management. Apart from data science, this is my day job and I feel like sharing my experience may help someone solve their problems. Some time ago, I hired a software engineer. The interview went fine, but the timeframe was strict and I missed a few questions that I usually ask. We were under heavy pressure, since projects were understaffed and we desperately needed people to keep up with the task stream. The slog of exhaustion, the need for help and a lack of success in hiring for weeks have done their job. I hired someone impulsively.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blazing fast category encoding</title><link href="/articles/datascience/blazing-encoders" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blazing fast category encoding" /><published>2021-09-15T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-09-15T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/articles/datascience/blazing-encoders</id><author><name>Kirill Dubovikov</name></author><category term="datascience" /><summary type="html">Category encoding can make a difference between bad and good machine learning modes. In this post, we will learn about target encoding with the blazing_encoders library.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Best time to post on HackerNews</title><link href="/articles/datascience/hn-posts-analysis" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best time to post on HackerNews" /><published>2021-07-02T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-07-02T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/articles/datascience/hn-posts-analysis</id><author><name>Kirill Dubovikov</name></author><category term="datascience" /><summary type="html">Let’s determine what the best time to post on HackerNews using statistical analysis and machine learning is.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Building a Weather Station UI</title><link href="/articles/rust/ui/weather-station-ui" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building a Weather Station UI" /><published>2020-11-04T19:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-11-04T19:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/articles/rust/ui/weather-station-ui</id><author><name>Kirill Dubovikov</name></author><category term="rust" /><category term="ui" /><summary type="html">In this last post of the series we are going to look at how to build a simple weather station UI dashboard.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Building a Weather Station Bot</title><link href="/articles/rust/building-a-weather-station-bot" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building a Weather Station Bot" /><published>2020-09-18T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-18T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/articles/rust/building-a-weather-station-bot</id><author><name>Kirill Dubovikov</name></author><category term="rust" /><summary type="html">In this post we are going to switch from hardware to software and write a telegram bot that will be the primary user interface for our weather station.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Async Unicorns love Rust</title><link href="/articles/rust/async-unicorns-love-rust" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Async Unicorns love Rust" /><published>2020-07-26T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-26T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/articles/rust/async-unicorns-love-rust</id><author><name>Kirill Dubovikov</name></author><category term="rust" /><summary type="html">Before going on to write a backend for our weather station we first need to familiarize ourselves with a few concepts from the Rust world. If you are unfamiliar with the language take a few minutes to read through Learn Rust in Y minutes to get used to the syntax. When we will write a Telegram bot with Rust, we will use a technique called asynchronous programming. Let’s tackle what that means.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Building yourself a weather station. Part 2</title><link href="/articles/hardware/build-yourself-a-weathe-station-part-2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building yourself a weather station. Part 2" /><published>2020-06-20T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-06-20T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/articles/hardware/build-yourself-a-weathe-station-part-2</id><author><name>Kirill Dubovikov</name></author><category term="hardware" /><summary type="html">In the previous post, we have covered the hardware setup for building a weather station. Starting from now, we will start coding. The first missing piece is the firmware for ESP32.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Build yourself a weather station. Part I</title><link href="/articles/hardware/build-yourself-a-weather-station" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Build yourself a weather station. Part I" /><published>2020-06-12T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-06-12T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/articles/hardware/build-yourself-a-weather-station</id><author><name>Kirill Dubovikov</name></author><category term="hardware" /><summary type="html">Intro I live pretty far away from the office, so my commute can take from 2.5 to 4 hours a day 😱. That includes a lot of time walking. I lost the count of times when I forgot to check if there was rain when going out from home. Or, even worse, the rain came in when I was midway to the train station. As a plus, the Weather app on my iPhone is not very good at making accurate forecasts. It can easily convince me that there is sunny outside when a sneaky rain starts to drop.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The beauty of hardware</title><link href="/articles/hardware/the-beauty-of-hardware" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The beauty of hardware" /><published>2020-04-27T20:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-27T20:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/articles/hardware/the-beauty-of-hardware</id><author><name>Kirill Dubovikov</name></author><category term="hardware" /><summary type="html">My life is tied to software. I first got interested in it in the year 2001, when I saw my father reading a C++ book. Since then, I learned and built and failed and learned again up to this day. Over those years, I’ve learned about different programming languages, peeked into the inner workings of operating systems, databases, and compilers. Back in the old days, I have tried to build simple bootloaders and operating systems in assembly using my old PC-iMac clone. Yet, somehow, I have always avoided getting into hardware. How does a CPU work? How RAM stores a single bit of memory? It was all black magic to me. Computers just worked. Maybe, your case is the same as mine. In this post, I will provide a short intro to digital electronics and give you some references on how to advance your studies further.</summary></entry></feed>