<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kirill Dubovikov</title>
    <description>My thoughts on everything :)</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:12:56 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:12:56 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building yourself a weather station. Part 2</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;writing-code-for-esp32&quot;&gt;Writing code for ESP32&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.kdubovikov.ml/articles/hardware/build-yourself-a-weather-station&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, we have covered the hardware setup for building a weather station. Starting from now, we will start coding. The first missing piece is the firmware for ESP32.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/articles/hardware/build-yourself-a-weathe-station-part-2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/articles/hardware/build-yourself-a-weathe-station-part-2</guid>
        
        
        <category>hardware</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Build yourself a weather station. Part I</title>
        <description>&lt;figure class=&quot;fullwidth&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/esp32-weather-station/post-1/weather-dashboard.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I live pretty far away from the office, so my commute can take from 2.5 to 4 hours a day 😱. That includes a lot of time walking. I lost the count of times when I forgot to check if there was rain when going out from home. Or, even worse, the rain came in when I was midway to the train station. As a plus, the Weather app on my iPhone is not very good at making accurate forecasts. It can easily convince me that there is sunny outside when a sneaky rain starts to drop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of months ago I started diving into the electronics, microcontrollers, and PCBs, so a side-project idea naturally came up to a surface. I’ll create a simple weather station that will check humidity and temperature outside every morning and notify me if I need to take an umbrella or warm clothes. This is a fun and easy IoT project from the hardware perspective, so I decided to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this series of posts, we will cover how to build an IoT weather station powered up by a web dashboard and Telegram bot. We will start from the birds-eye view first and cover the architecture of what we are going to make.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/articles/hardware/build-yourself-a-weather-station</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/articles/hardware/build-yourself-a-weather-station</guid>
        
        
        <category>hardware</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The beauty of hardware</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My life is tied to software. I first got interested in it in the year 2001, when I saw my father reading a C++ book. Since then, I learned and built and failed and learned again up to this day. Over those years, I’ve learned about different programming languages, peeked into the inner workings of operating systems, databases, and compilers. Back in the old days, I have tried to build simple bootloaders and operating systems in assembly using my old PC-iMac clone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, somehow, I have always avoided getting into hardware. How does a CPU work? How RAM stores a single bit of memory? It was all black magic to me. Computers just worked. Maybe, your case is the same as mine. In this post, I will provide a short intro to digital electronics and give you some references on how to advance your studies further.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/articles/hardware/the-beauty-of-hardware</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/articles/hardware/the-beauty-of-hardware</guid>
        
        
        <category>hardware</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
